# **Daniel Macready**

## **Chemical Engineer - Lerro Products**

Mount Laurel, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Daniel-Macready/791d0308464eb008

To gain an opportunity in which my broad spectrum of hands-on experience and academic training will continue to develop while improving the bottom line of a successful company.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Chemical Engineer**

Lerro Products - Camden, NJ - 2010 to Present

Manufacturer of Detergents and Disinfectants / Maintenance of Commercial Swimming Pools

- > Federal, State and Local Compliance Leader and Quality Control Supervisor
- > Construction, Maintenance and Optimization of Blending Tanks
- > Complete Construction of New Facility

#### **Anaerobic Digester Lead Operator**

Burlington County R&D Greenhouse - Columbus, NJ - 2006 to 2010

Columbus, NJ (2006-2010) Type IV Research

Business incubator dedicated to the economic development of new technologies in real world conditions

- > Anaerobic Digester Lead Operator: construction, data collection and analysis of a pilot-scale process for the production of biogas from food waste and horse manure
- > Management of Fully Automated 60k ft2 Greenhouse: worked simultaneously with multiple tenant requirements to achieve numerous parameter requirements
- > Hardware/Software Troubleshooting, Calibration and Programming of Argus® Control System
- > Installation of 250 kW Biogas Microturbine fed by Bio-Reactive Landfill and Anaerobic Digester
- > Integrated Aquaculture-Hydroponic Production System: optimization, maintenance/repair, upgrades
- > Hydroponic Tomato Yield & Production Experiments: design, set-up, data collection and analysis

#### **Assistant Superintendent**

Medford Lakes Country Club - Medford Lakes, NJ - 2002 to 2006

Training, Supervision and Management of a 15-20 Member Workforce

- > Heavy Equipment Operation & Maintenance (Interim Mechanic-2005)
- > Construction/Civil Engineering: Complete Renovation of 9 holes, Installation of 2 acre Irrigation Lake
- > Compliance: OSHA, NJDEP, EPA, Pinelands, Wetlands, Watershed and Township Regulations
- > Lead Irrigation Technician: Toro Sitepro® Programming, Operation, Expansion and Repair
- > Lead Pesticide and Fertilizer Technician: IPM, Disease Identification, Calibration and Application

#### **Assistant Manager**

The San Juan Room - Durango, CO - 1997 to 2002

Training, Supervision, and Management of a 20-30 Member Workforce

> Budgeting, Promotions, Cash Management, Marketing, Inventory, Customer Service and Security

#### SKILL SET:

- > Full spectrum from Labor & Trades to Software Programming and Modeling
- > ChemCad®, MatLab®, Maple®, Simulink®, Argus®, Java/C++®, Microsoft Office® Proficiency
- > Process Unit Design, Costing, Installation, Operation, Maintenance, Troubleshooting and Repair

## **EDUCATION**

# **B.S.** in Chemical Engineering

**Rutgers University** 

## A.S. in Environmental Science

Burlington County College

## **Turf Management**

**Rutgers University** 

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

> Trade Skills - Plumbing, Pumps, Motors, Agriculture, Hardscaping, Electrical, Heavy Equipment Operation, Sensors, Control Systems, Laboratory, Too Many To List